<root><debateinfo>
        <title>PROCLAMATION</title>
        <page.no>16</page.no>
        <type>proclamations</type>
      </debateinfo>
      <speech>
          <talk.start>
            <talker>
              <page.no>27</page.no>
              <time.stamp />
              <name.id>KQP</name.id>
              <electorate>Kennedy, Queensland</electorate>
              <party />
              <role />
              <in.gov>0</in.gov>
              <first.speech>0</first.speech>
              <name role="metadata">MCDONALD, Charles</name>
              <name role="display">Mr McDONALD</name>
            </talker>
            <para>- I understand; that this is the stage at which I can say a word or two. We were distinctly told by the Premier that the object the Government had in view was to take the Standing Orders of the Legislatures of the various States, and from them to formulate Standing Orders for the conduct of business in this House: Having said that, the right honorable gentleman objected to my saying anything at all, simply because he had spoken in reply. It is a common thing in the Queensland Assembly for an honorable member to speak after the mover of a motion has spoken in reply ; and, under the circumstances, I might have been excused for trying to take the opportunity to speak. I did not wish to put you, <inline font-weight="bold">Mr. Speaker,</inline> in any uncomfortable position, or  to be disrespectful to this House. What I wanted to know was this : We are going to meet here to-morrow morning at eleven o'clock without any Standing Orders. We do not know even what a quorum is. There may be ten members present, or there may be a full House. </para>
          </talk.start>
          <interjection>
            <talk.start>
              <talker>
                <page.no>27</page.no>
                <time.stamp />
                <name.id>009LR</name.id>
                <electorate />
                <party />
                <role />
                <in.gov>0</in.gov>
                <first.speech>0</first.speech>
                <name role="metadata">BARTON, Edmund</name>
                <name role="display">Mr Barton</name>
              </talker>
              <para>-  The Constitution enacts what a. quorum shall be. </para>
            </talk.start>
          </interjection>
          <continue>
            <talk.start>
              <talker>
                <page.no>27</page.no>
                <time.stamp />
                <name.id>KQP</name.id>
                <electorate />
                <party />
                <role />
                <in.gov>0</in.gov>
                <first.speech>0</first.speech>
                <name role="metadata">MCDONALD, Charles</name>
                <name role="display">Mr McDONALD</name>
              </talker>
              <para>- Well, that may be so; but, at any rate, we are expected to deal to-morrow morning - almost in a few minutes - with standing orders of a temporary character, and the Premier asks us to take them without debate. </para>
            </talk.start>
          </continue>
          <interjection>
            <talk.start>
              <talker>
                <page.no>27</page.no>
                <time.stamp />
                <name.id>009LR</name.id>
                <electorate />
                <party />
                <role />
                <in.gov>0</in.gov>
                <first.speech>0</first.speech>
                <name role="metadata">BARTON, Edmund</name>
                <name role="display">Mr Barton</name>
              </talker>
              <para>-  I did not say so. I said that I should lay the proposed standing orders on the table to-morrow morning, that they would be afterwards distributed, and that, when we met on the 21st, I should ask honorable members to accept those standing orders for the short interval that must elapse before the Standing Orders Committee can get to work. </para>
            </talk.start>
          </interjection>
          <continue>
            <talk.start>
              <talker>
                <page.no>27</page.no>
                <time.stamp />
                <name.id>KQP</name.id>
                <electorate />
                <party />
                <role />
                <in.gov>0</in.gov>
                <first.speech>0</first.speech>
                <name role="metadata">MCDONALD, Charles</name>
                <name role="display">Mr McDONALD</name>
              </talker>
              <para>- If my memory does not deceive me, the right honorable gentleman said that he hoped there would not be two debates on the standing orders. </para>
            </talk.start>
          </continue>
          <interjection>
            <talk.start>
              <talker>
                <page.no>27</page.no>
                <time.stamp />
                <name.id>009LR</name.id>
                <electorate />
                <party />
                <role />
                <in.gov>0</in.gov>
                <first.speech>0</first.speech>
                <name role="metadata">BARTON, Edmund</name>
                <name role="display">Mr Barton</name>
              </talker>
              <para>-  Hear, hear. </para>
            </talk.start>
          </interjection>
          <continue>
            <talk.start>
              <talker>
                <page.no>27</page.no>
                <time.stamp />
                <name.id>KQP</name.id>
                <electorate />
                <party />
                <role />
                <in.gov>0</in.gov>
                <first.speech>0</first.speech>
                <name role="metadata">MCDONALD, Charles</name>
                <name role="display">Mr McDONALD</name>
              </talker>
              <para>- I think that is the very reason why we should have the proposed standing orders the first thing to-morrow morning. </para>
            </talk.start>
          </continue>
          <interjection>
            <talk.start>
              <talker>
                <page.no>27</page.no>
                <time.stamp />
                <name.id>009LR</name.id>
                <electorate />
                <party />
                <role />
                <in.gov>0</in.gov>
                <first.speech>0</first.speech>
                <name role="metadata">BARTON, Edmund</name>
                <name role="display">Mr Barton</name>
              </talker>
              <para>-  Honorable members will have them then. </para>
            </talk.start>
          </interjection>
          <continue>
            <talk.start>
              <talker>
                <page.no>27</page.no>
                <time.stamp />
                <name.id>KQP</name.id>
                <electorate />
                <party />
                <role />
                <in.gov>0</in.gov>
                <first.speech>0</first.speech>
                <name role="metadata">MCDONALD, Charles</name>
                <name role="display">Mr McDONALD</name>
              </talker>
              <para>- I am sorry that the Government did not lay them on the table to-night, so that by to-morrow morning we might know exactly what they contain. </para>
            </talk.start>
          </continue>
          <para class="block">The right honorable gentleman does not for one moment suppose that when we get the standing orders we shall be able to take in at a glance exactly what is proposed. There may be very objectionable features in them, and, as I have had considerable difficulties in connexion with standing orders in another State, I am not going to allow any standing orders to pass in this House without entering my protest against them. </para>
        </speech>
      </root>