<root><debateinfo>
        <title>PROCLAMATION</title>
        <page.no>16</page.no>
        <type>proclamations</type>
      </debateinfo>
      <speech>
          <talk.start>
            <talker>
              <page.no>23</page.no>
              <time.stamp />
              <name.id>L2G</name.id>
              <electorate>Wentworth</electorate>
              <party />
              <role />
              <in.gov>0</in.gov>
              <first.speech>0</first.speech>
              <name role="metadata">MCMILLAN, William</name>
              <name role="display">Sir WILLIAM McMILLAN</name>
            </talker>
            <para>- On behalf of the right honorable member for East Sydney, who is prevented through illness from being here to-day - an illness which, I am sure, will be deplored by honorable members on both sides of the House - I have the honour, on behalf of the Opposition in this Chamber, to give you, <inline font-weight="bold">Mr. Speaker,</inline> a hearty welcome to that high and dignified position to which you have been elected. It is with mixed feelings, if you will not misunderstand me, that I welcome you to that chair. Though it is an honour to our party that one of outnumber should have been selected for that great and high office, it is an undoubted loss to us to be deprived of one of our most brilliant members. I agree with the right honorable gentleman who has just sat down that we have in the chair not only a man who is well versed in parliamentary practice, but also a gentleman of highly honorable character - and character is, in the long run, the test of public life. I also know, although you are a loss to our side, that for many years you have undertaken arduous duties in the Assembly of South Australia ; and it is a consolation to know that now you are resting and becoming non-partisan in the strictest sense, you will have an opportunity of recruiting your health. I hope that the duties of that chair will not be so extremely onerous as have been the duties of Speakers in some Parliaments in Australia, and that you will be able to keep us within reasonable hours in the performance of our legislative functions. It is a matter of congratulation that, at this the first event in our parliamentary career, no acrimonious debate has taken place, and that you are elected our  Speaker  and the First Commoner of Australia by the unanimous consent of this Chamber. On behalf of the Opposition, <inline font-weight="bold">Sir, I</inline> heartily congratulate you on your dignity. </para>
          </talk.start>
        </speech>
        </root>