<root><debateinfo>
        <title>PROCLAMATION</title>
        <page.no>16</page.no>
        <type>proclamations</type>
      </debateinfo>
      <speech>
          <talk.start>
            <talker>
              <page.no>20</page.no>
              <time.stamp />
              <name.id>KIQ</name.id>
              <electorate>Brisbane</electorate>
              <party />
              <role />
              <in.gov>0</in.gov>
              <first.speech>0</first.speech>
              <name role="metadata">MACDONALD-PATERSON, Thomas</name>
              <name role="display">Mr MACDONALD-PATERSON</name>
            </talker>
            <para>- I move - </para>
          </talk.start>
          <quote>
            <para>That <inline font-weight="bold">Mr. Frederick</inline> William Holder do take the chair of the House as  Speaker. </para>
          </quote>
          <para class="block">The position to which I propose that <inline font-weight="bold">Mr. Holder</inline> should be elected is a magnificent one, but I think that the honour will be accorded to  him unanimously, because honorable members will agree that in electing him to preside over the deliberations of this House we shall be putting the right man into the right place. Many honorable members have known <inline font-weight="bold">Mr. Holder</inline> for a much longer time than that during which I have known him ; but I feel sure that all will agree that the part he has played in the advancement of the federation of the Australian States has been a great one. If he had been physically a little stronger I think his voice and his presence would have been more generally heard and felt throughout the States, but he was prevented from taking the opportunity to make himself more generally known, for this reason, and because of responsibilities which he could not forsake. So far as the representatives from the State of Queensland are concerned, we are unanimously of opinion that, in electing <inline font-weight="bold">Mr.</inline></para>
          <para class="block">Holder to the position of honour in which I have proposed he shall be placed, we shall be choosing a man who will do great credit to it. He is known for his suavity and urbanity of manner; he is unquestionably a man of great judgment and of large experience; and although some may- regard his nicelybalanced mind and quiet demeanour as perhaps an evidence of weakness of character, I am sure that in his heart and breast there rests the ability and vitality to be firm, strong, and diplomatic. In electing <inline font-weight="bold">Mr. Holder,</inline> Ave  shall be choosing a  Speaker  who will fill the position with credit to this assembly, with much honour to himself, and with dignity to the Commonwealth. </para>
        </speech>
        </root>