<root><debateinfo>
        <title>PROCLAMATION</title>
        <page.no>16</page.no>
        <type>proclamations</type>
      </debateinfo>
      <speech>
          <talk.start>
            <talker>
              <page.no>22</page.no>
              <time.stamp />
              <name.id>KHI</name.id>
              <electorate>South Australia</electorate>
              <party />
              <role />
              <in.gov>0</in.gov>
              <first.speech>0</first.speech>
              <name role="metadata">HOLDER, Frederick</name>
              <name role="display">Mr HOLDER</name>
            </talker>
            <para>- I respectfully submit myself to the will of the House. </para>
          </talk.start>
          <para>Members of the House calling <inline font-weight="bold">Mr. Holder</inline> to the chair, he was taken out of his place by <inline font-weight="bold">Mr. Macdonald-paterson</inline> and <inline font-weight="bold">Sir Edward</inline> Braddon and conducted to the chair. </para>
          <para>Then <inline font-weight="bold">Mr. Speaker</inline> elect, standing on the upper step, said - I must express, as deeply and clearly as words will permit, my deep sense of the obligation  which rests upon me in consequence of the honour which the House has unanimously conferred upon me. I recognise the importance of the position to which I have been summoned, and I realize at least some of its responsibilities as well as its high honour. I shall seek as time may go by to maintain the high reputation which the office of  Speaker  has hitherto borne in all parts of our great Empire. I am quite sure that though honorable members will have to express their deep and earnest convictions on the various matters that come before the House they will express them with due respect to our standing orders. I rely, as I am sure I have a right to rely, upon the earnest support and assistance of every member of this House to assist me in maintaining order according to our regulations. I am glad to be able to thank the Government for the excellent staff they have placed at our disposal, and I am quite sure that by their aid, and with the support of honorable members, I shall be .able to fulfil, at least to some extent, those anticipations which have been so kindly expressed. I thank honorable members for the honour they have done me. </para>
        </speech>
        </root>