<root><debateinfo>
        <title>PROCLAMATION</title>
        <page.no>16</page.no>
        <type>proclamations</type>
      </debateinfo>
      <speech>
          <talk.start>
            <talker>
              <page.no>22</page.no>
              <time.stamp />
              <name.id>009LR</name.id>
              <electorate>Hunter</electorate>
              <party>Protectionist</party>
              <role>Minister for External Affairs</role>
              <in.gov>1</in.gov>
              <first.speech>0</first.speech>
              <name role="metadata">BARTON, Edmund</name>
              <name role="display">Mr BARTON</name>
            </talker>
            <para>. - -I have to express to you, <inline font-weight="bold">Mr. Speaker,</inline> in conjunction with one of my honorable friends opposite, who will follow me, the entire congratulations of this House upon the position of dignity and honour to which you have attained. There is no man who has been a keen watcher of the progress of the federal movement in Australia who has not become conscious years ago of the strength and force and also the persuasive influence which your advocacy has given to that movement. Many of us have gone through that long and arduous struggle with conflicting feelings and emotions, but those who were first in the fight were always able to put a strong reliance Upon each other, and in that strong reliance upon yon, sir, I have always found myself to be justified. Tour long Parliamentary experience and your known acquaintance with Parliamentary usage and practice, I take it, will be considered to eminently justify the selection of this House. It is true that my honorable friend, who proposed you for this office, has made reference to the amiability which in some quarters might be mistaken for weakness. But I am one of those who believe that courtesy is the first condition of dignity, without which dignity the respect of a great free representative assembly cannot be commanded. And so I have no fear for the future, <inline font-weight="bold">Sir, in</inline> that courtesy of yours which is your natural characteristic, and which is demanded of every  speaker  by the traditions and usages and the every day conditions of Parliamentary action. The  speaker  who is not courteous to all members of the House cannot expect their consistent support, for an affront offered to one is an affront offered to all. That, however, we cannot expect from you, but so much to thecontrary. We are confident from your past that you will uphold all that is valuable in Parliamentary precedent, all that is right and just in Parliamentary action, by a firmness which is perfectly compatible with that courtesy we all know you to possess. I must express, also, my personal gratification. From a long acquaintance with you - a friendship, I hope I may say - I am able to say to those who do not know you as well perhaps as I do, that we are electing to the Chair of this House a gentleman and an honourable and upright man. </para>
          </talk.start>
        </speech>
        </root>